[
    {
        "question": "1.The advent of project management has been most profound in\nA.Automobile manufacturing\nB.Construction\nC.Information technology\nD.The U.S. Department of Defense\nE.Film  making",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "C.",
        "help": "The impact of project management is most profound in the area of electronics industry, where the new folk heroesare young professionals whose Herculean efforts lead to the constant flow of new hardware and software products. hinking",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "2.A professional organization for project management specialists is the\nA.PMI\nB.AMA\nC.MIS\nD.IPM\nE.PMBOK",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "A.",
        "help": "The Project Management Institute (PMI), is a professional organization for project managers. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "3.Which of the following is not considered to be a characteristic of a project?\nA.An established objective\nB.A cl ear beginning and end\nC.Complex tasks\nD.Only for internal use\nE.Never been done before",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "D.",
        "help": "See List on Page 5. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "4.Which of the following activities is  not considered a project?\nA.Developing a new software program\nB.Designing a space station\nC.Preparing the site for the Olympic Games\nD.Production of automobile tires\nE.Developing a new advertising program",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "D.",
        "help": "A project is not routine, repetitive work! Ordinary daily work typically requires doing the same or similar work over and over, while a project is done onlyonce; a new product or service exists when the project is completed. t?",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "5.From among the following activities, which is the best example of a project?\nA.Processing insurance claims\nB.Producing automobiles\nC.Writing a term paper\nD.Completing a college degree\nE.All of these are good examples of project s",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "C.",
        "help": "See table 1.1 on Page 6. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "6.Which of the following constraints is not typically found in managing projects?\nA.Time\nB.People\nC.Cost\nD.Performance\nE.Both B an d D are not typical constraints",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "B.",
        "help": "Specific time, cost, and performance requirements bind projects. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "7.Which of the following choices is not one of the stages of  a project life cycle?\nA.Conceptualizing\nB.Defining\nC.Planning\nD.Executing\nE.Delivering",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "A.",
        "help": "See List on Page 7. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "8.In which of the following stages are project o bjectives established, teams formed, and major responsibilities assigned?\nA.Conceptualizing\nB.Defining\nC.Planning\nD.Executing\nE.Delivering",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "B.",
        "help": "Specifications of the project are defined; project objectives are established; teams are formed; major responsibilities are assigned. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "9.In which of the following stages is a major portion of the physical and mental project work performed?\nA.Conceptualizing\nB.Definin g\nC.Planning\nD.Executing\nE.Delivering",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "D.",
        "help": "A major portion of the project work takes placeâ€”both physical and mental. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "10.In which of the following stages are you  more likely to find status reports, many changes, and the creation of forecasts?\nA.Conceptualizing\nB.Defining\nC.Planning\nD.Executing\nE.Delivering",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "D.",
        "help": "Time, cost, and specification measures are used for control. Learning Objective: What is a Project?",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "11.Which of the following characteristics is not typical of a project manager?\nA.Managing a temporary activity\nB.Possesses in-depth technical knowledge\nC.Managing a non-repetitive activity\nD.Manages  independently of the formal organization\nE.Provides a direct link to the customer",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "B.",
        "help": "Increased competition has placed a premium on customer satisfaction. Customers no longer simply settle for genericproducts and services. is",
        "difficulty": "Level: Difficult"
    },
    {
        "question": "12.Which of the following choices is not one of the driving forces behind the increasing demand for project management?\nA.Compression of the product life cycle\nB.Knowledge  explosion\nC.Development of third world and closed economies\nD.More emphasis on the product and less on the customer\nE.Corporate downsizing",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "D.",
        "help": "Increased customer attention has prompted the development of customized products and services. e Thinking",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "13.Which of the following statements is true?\nA.Project management is becoming a standard way of doing business\nB.Project management is increasingl y contributing to achieving organizational strategies\nC.Project management is being used at a consistent percentage of a firm's efforts\nD.Both A and B are true\nE.A, B, and C are all true",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "D.",
        "help": "Project management is no longer a special-need management. It is rapidly becoming a standard way of doing business. The future promises an increase in the importance and the roleof projects in contributing to the strategic direction of organizations. Learning Objective: The Importance of Project Management",
        "difficulty": "Level: Difficult"
    },
    {
        "question": "14.Project management is ideally suited for a business environment requiring all of the following except\nA.Accountability\nB.Flexibility\nC.Innovation\nD.Speed\nE.Repeatability",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "E.",
        "help": "Competing in a global market influenced by rapid change, innovation, and time to market means organizations manage more and moreprojects. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "15.W hich of the following is the number one characteristic that is looked for in management candidates?\nA.Overall intelligence\nB.Works well with others\nC.Experience\nD.Past successes\nE.Good references",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "B.",
        "help": "The phrase \"works well with others\" has long been a staple on grade school report cards; now, in the IT world, it's the No. 1 criterion for management candidates.(SeeResearch Highlight on page 16). roach",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "16.A common rule of thumb in the world of high-tech product development is that a six-month project delay can result in a loss of product revenue share of ___ percent. The waste on failed projects and cost overruns is estimated in t he neighborhood of\nA.10\nB.20\nC.33\nD.45\nE.50",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "C.",
        "help": "A common rule of thumb in the world of high-tech product development is that a six-month project delay can resultin a 33 percent loss in product revenue share. Learning Objective: The Importance of Project Management",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "17.The waste on failed projects and cost overruns is estimated in the neighborhood of\nA.Under $100 Million\nB.Over $150 Billon\nC.Under $10 Billion\nD.Between $90-$100 Billion\nE.Betw een $125-$135 Billion",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "B.",
        "help": "The need for elevating performance continues to challenge the project management profession. The waste on failedprojects and cost overruns is estimated in the neighborhood of over $150 billion! Learning Objective: What is a Project?",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "18.Which of the following is the first step in developing a set of strategies designed to best meet the needs of customers?\nA.Market Research\nB.Define the Integrated Project Management System\nC.Envi ronmental Analysis\nD.Project Selection\nE.All of the above are correct",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "C.",
        "help": "Project management is critical both to development of customized products and services and to sustaining lucrativerelationships with customers. Learning Objective: The Importance of Project Management",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "19.Integration of project management with the organization takes place with the\nA.Master budget\nB.Strategy plan\nC.Process of managing actual projects\nD.Both b and c are correct\nE.A, B, and C are all correct",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "D.",
        "help": "Since projects are the modus operandi, strategic alignment of projects is of major importance to conserving andeffective use of organization resources. Selection criteria need to ensure each project is prioritized andcontributes to strategic goals. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "20.Two dimensions within the project management process are\nA.Technical and sociocultural\nB.Cost and tim e\nC.Planned and unexpected\nD.Established and new\nE.Unique and reoccurring",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "A.",
        "help": "There are two dimensions within the actual execution of projects (see Figure 1.3. The Technical and SocioculturalDimensions of the Project Management Process on page 15). AACSB: Analytic",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "21.Which of these is not part of the \"technical dimension\" of project management?\nA.WBS\nB.Budgets\nC.Problem solving\nD.Schedules\nE.Stat us reports",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "C.",
        "help": "See Figure 1.3. The Technical and Sociocultural Dimensions of the Project Management Process on page 15. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "22.Which of th ese is not part of the \"sociocultural dimension\" of project management?\nA.Negotiation\nB.Resource allocation\nC.Customer expectations\nD.Leadership\nE.Politics",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "B.",
        "help": "See Figure 1.3. The Technical and Sociocultural Dimensions of the Project Management Process on page 15. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "23.Corporate downsizing has increased the trend toward\nA.Reducing the number of projects a company initiates\nB.Ou tsourcing significant segments of project work\nC.Using dedicated project teams\nD.Shorter project lead times\nE.Longer project lead times",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "B.",
        "help": "Companies outsource significant segments of project work, and project managers have to manage not only theirown people but also their counterparts in different organizations. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "24.The importance of project management has increased due to\nA.The movement of  manufacturing operations out of the U.S\nB.Time to market\nC.The movement toward flatter and leaner organizations\nD.Both a and b are true\nE.A, B, and C are all true",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "E.",
        "help": "One of the most significant driving forces behind the demand for project management is the shortening of the product life cycle. In today's flatter and leaner organizations, where change is a constant,project management is replacing middle management as a way of ensuring that things get done. Corporate downsizinghas also led to a change in the way organizations approach projects. Companies outsource significant segments of project work, and projectmanagers have to manage not only their own people but also their counterparts in different organizations. Learning Objective: The Importance of Project Management",
        "difficulty": "Level: Difficult"
    },
    {
        "question": "25.Which of the following is not typically the responsibility of a project manger?\nA.Meeting budget requirements\nB.Meeting schedule requirements\nC.Meeting performance specifica tions\nD.Coordinates the actions of the team members\nE.All of these are typical responsibilities",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "E.",
        "help": "They must ensure that appropriate trade-offs are made between the time, cost, and performance requirements ofthe project. ge",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "26.A series of coordinated, related, multiple projects that continue over extended time intended to achieve a goal is known as a\nA.Strategy\nB.Program\nC.Campaign\nD.Crusade\nE.Venture",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "B.",
        "help": "A program is a group of related projects designed to accomplish a common goal over an extended period of time. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "27.In which of the following stages is it determined what th e project will entail, when it will be scheduled, whom it will benefit, and what the budget will be?\nA.Conceptualizing\nB.Defining\nC.Planning\nD.Executing\nE.Delivering",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "C.",
        "help": "The level of effort increases, and plans are developed to determine what the projectwill entail, when it will be scheduled, whom it will benefit, what quality level should be maintained, and whatthe budget will be. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "28.Competing in a global m arket is influenced by\nA.Rapid change\nB.Innovation\nC.Time to market\nD.Politics\nE.A, B, and C are all true",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "E.",
        "help": "Competing in a global market influenced by rapid change, innovation, and time to market means organizations managemore and more projects. AACSB: Analytic",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "29.Integration of all project processes and practices to improve Project Management is due to\nA.Centralization\nB.Environmental anal ysis\nC.Customer Expectations\nD.Project management system\nE.The organization's environment and culture",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "A.",
        "help": "Centralization entails integration of all project processes and practices to improve project management. Learning Objective: Project Management Today - An Integrated Approach",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "30.From 1994 to 2009 the trend for projects late or over budget was:\nA.Significantly better\nB.Slightly better\nC.About the same\nD.Slightly worse\nE.Significantly worse",
        "type": "multipleChoice",
        "answer": "B.",
        "help": "Failed projects also declined from 31 percent in 1994 to 18 percent in 2004. However, the CHAOS Summary 2009 reportshows a small decrease in the numbers. Fill in the Blank Questions",
        "difficulty": "the Blank Questions"
    },
    {
        "question": "31.Like most organizational effort, the major goal of a project is to __________.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "satisfy a customer's need",
        "help": "Like most organizational effort, the major goal of a project is to satisfy a customer's need. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "32.The initial stage in the Project Life Cycle is the __________ stage.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "defining",
        "help": "Specifications of the project are defined; project objectives are established; teams are formed; major responsibilities are assigned. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "33.The final stage in the Project Life Cycle is the __________ stage.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "closure",
        "help": "Closure includes three activities: delivering the project product to the customer, redeploying project resources, and post-project review. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "34.The __________, a professional organizati on for project managers, has grown from 93,000 in 2002 to more than 230,000 currently.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "PMI",
        "help": "The Project Management Institute (PMI), is a professional organization for project managers. : What is a Project?",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "35.In the __________ stage of the Project Life Cycle a major part of the project work, both physical and mental, takes place.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "executing",
        "help": "A major portion of the project work takes placeâ€”both physical and mental.  Reflective Thinking",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "36.In the _________ stage of the Project Life Cycle what will be accomplished by the project is determined along with the project's schedule and budget. plann",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "planning",
        "help": "The level of effort increases, and plans are developed to determine what the project will entail, when it willbe scheduled, whom it will benefit, what quality level should be maintained, and what the budget will be. Bloom's: Application",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "37.A common rule of thumb in the world of high-tech product development is that a six-month project delay can result in a __________ percent loss in product revenue share.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "thirty-three",
        "help": "A common rule of thumb in the world of high-tech product development is that a six-month project delay can resultin a 33 percent loss in product revenue share. ent",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "38.In today's high-tech industries the product life cycle is averaging _________ years.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "1 to 3",
        "help": "Today in high-tech industries the product life cycle is averaging 1 to 3 years. Only 30 years ago, life cyclesof 10 to 15 years were not uncommon. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "39.The advent of many small projects has created the need for an organization that can support __________ management. multip",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "multiproject",
        "help": "This climate has created a multiproject environment and a plethora of new problems. Sharing and prioritizingresources across a portfolio of projects is a major challenge for senior management. Learning Objective: The Importance of Project Management",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "40.Increased competition has placed a premium on customer satisfaction and the development of __________ products and services.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "customized",
        "help": "Customers want customized products and services that cater to their specific needs. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "41.In some organizations, selection and management of projects often fail to support the broad-based  _________ of the organization.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "strategic plan",
        "help": "Today, projects are the modus operandi for implementing strategy. Yet in some organizations, selection and managementof projects often fail to support the strategic plan of the organization. c",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "42.WBS, schedules, and budgets are examples of the _________ dimension of the project management process.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "technical",
        "help": "See Figure 1.3. The Technical and Sociocultural Dimensions of the Project Management Process on page 15. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "43.Leadership, teamwork, and negotiation are example s of the _________ dimension of the project management process.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "sociocultural",
        "help": "See Figure 1.3. The Technical and Sociocultural Dimensions of the Project Management Process on page 15. nagement Today - An Integrated Approach",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "44.The ________ is a professional organization for project management specialists.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "Project Management Institute (PMI)",
        "help": "The Project Management Institute (PMI), is a professional organization for project managers. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "45.One of the defining characteristics of a project is that it has a singular purpose, i.e., an established ________.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "objective",
        "help": "Projects have a defined objectiveâ€”whether it is constructing a 12-story apartment complex by January 1 or releasing version 2.0 of a specific softwarepackage as quickly as possible. sy",
        "difficulty": "sy"
    },
    {
        "question": "46.Because projects have a defined beginning and end, the ________ is frequently used to manage the transition of a project from start to completion.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "Project Life Cycle",
        "help": "The project life cycle typically passes sequentially through four stages: defining, planning, executing, and delivering. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Difficult"
    },
    {
        "question": "47.The development of schedules, budgets, and identifying risks are common elements to the ________ stage of the proje ct life cycle.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "planning",
        "help": "The level of effort increases, and plans are developed to determine what the project will entail, when it willbe scheduled, whom it will benefit, what quality level should be maintained, and what the budget will be. ective Thinking",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "48.The establishment of project goals, specifications, and responsibilities usually occurs in the ________ stage of the project life cycle.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "defining",
        "help": "Specifications of the project are defined; project objectives are established; teams are formed; major responsibilities areassigned. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "49.Training the customer, r eassigning staff, and releasing resources occurs in the ________ stage of the project life cycle.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "closure",
        "help": "Includes three activities: delivering the project product to the customer, redeploying project resources, andpost-project review. Delivery of the project might include customer training and transferring documents. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "50.Project managers are expected to ensure that appropriate trade-offs are made bet ween the time, cost, and __________ requirements of the project.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "performance",
        "help": "Project managers are ultimately responsible for performance (frequently with too little authority). They mustensure that appropriate trade-offs are made between the time, cost, and performance requirements of the project. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "51.The growth in ________ has increased the complexity of projects because projects typically include the latest adva nces.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "new knowledge",
        "help": "The growth in new knowledge has increased the complexity of projects because projects encompass the latest advances.Product complexity has increased the need to integrate divergent technologies. Project management has emergedas an important discipline for achieving this task. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "52.A _________ is a series of coordinated, related; multiple projects that continue over extended ti me intended to achieve a goal.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "program",
        "help": "A program is a group of related projects designed to accomplish a common goal over an extended period of time. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "53.In the  __________ stage, it determined what the project will entail, when it will be scheduled, whom it will benefit, and what the budget will be.",
        "type": "fill-in",
        "answer": "planning",
        "help": "The level of effort increases, and plans are developed to determine what the project will entail, when it will be scheduled, whom it will benefit, what quality level should be maintained, and what the budget will be. True / False Questions",
        "difficulty": "True / False Questions"
    },
    {
        "question": "54.Because  of the profitability motive, project management is nearly always limited to the private sector.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "FALSE",
        "help": "Project management is not limited to the private sector. Project management is also a vehicle for doing gooddeeds and solving social problems. : Reflective Thinking",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "55.Ten years ago major universities offered only one or two classes in project management, primarily for engineers.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "TRUE",
        "help": "Ten years ago major universities offered one or two classes in project management, primarily for engineers. Today, most universities offer multiplesections of project management classes, with the core group of engineers being supplemented by business studentsmajoring in marketing, management information systems (MIS). ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "56.The professional certification for project managers is a Project Management Professional (PMP).",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "TRUE",
        "help": "PMI provides certification as a Project Management Professional (PMP)â€”someone who has documented sufficient project experience, agreed to follow the PMI code of professional conduct,and demonstrated mastery of the field of project management by passing a comprehensive examination. (See Snapshot on Page 4). ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "57.Because of its flexibility, project management is equally useful in ongoing, routine work as well as unique, on e-time projects.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "FALSE",
        "help": "A project is not routine, repetitive work! Ordinary daily work typically requires doing the same or similar workover and over, while a project is done only once; a new product or service exists when the project is completed. AACSB: Reflective Thinking",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "58.One of the defining characteristics of project management is that the projects are not confined to a single department but involve several departments and  professionals.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "TRUE",
        "help": "One of the major characteristics is the involvement of several departments and professionals. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "59.One of the characteristics t hat separate project management from other endeavors of the organization is that there are specific time, cost, and performance requirements.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "TRUE",
        "help": "Major characteristics are specific time, cost, and performance requirements. Bloom's: Comprehension",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "60.The singular purpose of a project is often lacking in daily organizational life in which workers perform repetitive operations each day.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "TRUE",
        "help": "This singular purpose is often lacking in daily organizational life in which workers perform repetitive operations each day. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "61.Since a construction company builds many buildings  the projects after the first building do not fit the definition of a project.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "FALSE",
        "help": "All projects are nonroutine and has some unique elements. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "62.The first stage in the Project Life Cyc le is the Concept stage.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "FALSE",
        "help": "The first stage is defining. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "63.A major portion of the project work, both physical and mental, takes place during the  Production stage of the Project Life Cycle.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "FALSE",
        "help": "A major portion of the project work, both physical and mental is done in the executing stage. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "64.I n practice, the amount of work accomplished in each stage of the Project Life Cycle will vary greatly depending on the department or work group.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "TRUE",
        "help": "In practice, the project life cycle is used by some project groups to depict the timing of major tasks over the life of the project. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "65.Because of the requirement for in-depth expertise, project management is generally restricted to specialists.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "FALSE",
        "help": "Unlike their functional counterparts, project managers generally possess only rudimentary technical knowledge. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "66.On the project team, the Marketing manage r is the primary, direct link with the customer.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "FALSE",
        "help": "Project Managers are typically the direct link to the customer and must manage the tension between customer expectationsand what is feasible and reasonable. wledge",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "67.One of the most significant driving forces behind the demand for project management is the ever increasing expansion of the product life cycle.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "FALSE",
        "help": "One of the most significant driving forces behind the demand for project management is the shortening of the product life cycle. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "68.Unlike their functional counterparts, proj ect managers generally possess only rudimentary technical knowledge to make trade-off decisions.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "TRUE",
        "help": "Unlike their functional counterparts, project managers generally possess only rudimentary technical knowledge. wledge",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "69.Because of the significant loss in potential product revenue, \"time to market\" has become one of the most critical factors in developing new products.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "TRUE",
        "help": "Time to market for new products with short life cycles has become increasingly important. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "70.A common rule of thumb in the world of high-tech product development is  that a six-month project delay can result in a 33 percent loss in product revenue share.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "TRUE",
        "help": "A common rule of thumb in the world of high-tech product development is that a six-month project delay can resultin a 33 percent loss in product revenue share. Speed, therefore, becomes a competitive advantage; more and more organizations are relying on cross-functionalproject teams to get new products and services to the market as quickly as possible. Learning Objective: The Importance of Project Management",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "71.Project management integration necessitates combining all of the major dimensions of project management under one umbrella.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "TRUE",
        "help": "Project management integration necessitates combining all ofthe major dimensions of project management under one umbrella. Each dimension is connected in one seamless, integrateddomain. Integration means applying a set of knowledge, skills, tools, and techniques to a collection of projectsin order to move the organization toward its strategic goals. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "72.Due to corporate downsizing significant segments of project work have been  outsourced to other organizations.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "TRUE",
        "help": "Corporate downsizing has also led to a change in the way organizations approach projects. Companies outsourcesignificant segments of project work, and project managers have to manage not only their own people but also their counterparts in different organizations. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "73.Smaller projects in larger organizations tend not to need project management skil ls.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "FALSE",
        "help": "Many small projects can eat up the people resources of a firm and represent hidden costs not measured in theaccounting system. Organizations with many small projects going on concurrently face the most difficult projectmanagement problems. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "74.In the current trends, Project managers are typically required to manage many diverse systems such as; networks, bar charts, job cos ting, task forces, partnering and schedule, to manage projects.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "FALSE",
        "help": "Project managers must shape a project culture that stimulates teamwork and high levels of personal motivationas well as a capacity to quickly identify and resolve problems that threaten project work. This dimension also involves managing the interface between the project and external environment.Project managers have to assuage and shape expectations of customers, sustain the political support of topmanagement, negotiate with their functional counterparts, monitor subcontractors, and so on. Overall, the manager must build a cooperative socialnetwork among a divergent set of allies with different standards, commitments, and perspectives. sion",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "75.Project management is usually restricted to specialists.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "FALSE",
        "help": "Unlike their functional counterparts, project managers generally possess only rudimentary technical knowledge. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "76.Project management is becoming a standard way of doing business.",
        "type": "boolean",
        "answer": "TRUE",
        "help": "Project management is no longer a special-need management. It is rapidly becoming a standard way of doing business. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy  Short Answer Questions"
    },
    {
        "question": "77.Compare and contrast the Product Life Cycle and  the Project Life Cycle.",
        "type": "shortAnswer",
        "answer": "",
        "help": "Product Life Cycle deals with the time it takes to develop a product and the time it remains in the marketplace.The Project Life Cycle is the stages that a new product goes through while being developed. : Analysis",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "78.Identify the five major characteristics of a project.",
        "type": "shortAnswer",
        "answer": "",
        "help": "see list on page 5 of your text a Project?",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "79.Identify and briefly describe the four stages of the Project Life Cycle.",
        "type": "shortAnswer",
        "answer": "",
        "help": "see list on page 1-7 ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Easy"
    },
    {
        "question": "80.\"Project managers perfo rm the same functions as other managers.\" Agree or Disagree and support your decision.",
        "type": "shortAnswer",
        "answer": "",
        "help": "Many of the same basic management functions are performed by project managers; however, there are aspects ofthe project manager's job that make it unique. alytic",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "81.Identify and briefly describe the six factors that are increasing the demand for project management.",
        "type": "shortAnswer",
        "answer": "",
        "help": "1. compression of the product life cycle, 2. knowledge explosion, 3. triple bottom line, 4. corporate downsizing, 5. increased customer focus, 6. small projects represent big problems ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Difficult"
    },
    {
        "question": "82.What is m eant by an \"Integrated Project Management Process\"?",
        "type": "shortAnswer",
        "answer": "",
        "help": "All efforts are focused toward the strategic plan. Piece meal tools are no longer accepted. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Difficult"
    },
    {
        "question": "83.Identify and briefly discuss the two key areas where project management need to be integrated within the organization.",
        "type": "shortAnswer",
        "answer": "",
        "help": "1. with the Strategic Plan and 2. within the process of managing actual projects mprehension",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "84.Identify and briefly discuss the two key dimensions of managing actual projects.",
        "type": "shortAnswer",
        "answer": "",
        "help": "1. Technical and 2. Sociocultural ion",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "85.The success of individual projects is typically measured by performance compared to three constraints usually placed on all projects. Identify and briefly describ e those three constraints.",
        "type": "shortAnswer",
        "answer": "",
        "help": "1. time, 2. cost, and 3. performance ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "86.Describe what it means that a Project Manager must work with a diverse troupe  of characters?",
        "type": "shortAnswer",
        "answer": "",
        "help": "They are typically the direct link to the customer and must manage the tension between customer expectationsand what is feasible and reasonable. Project managers provide direction, coordination, and integration tothe project team, which is often made up of part-time participants loyal to their functional departments. They often must work with acadre of outsidersâ€”vendors, suppliers, subcontractorsâ€”who do not necessarily share their project allegiance. Learning Objective: What is a Project?",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "87.What is the difference between a project and a program?",
        "type": "shortAnswer",
        "answer": "",
        "help": "The terms are often used interchangeably in business, however, a program is considered to be a series of coordinated,related, and multiple projects that continue over extended time intended to achieve a goal. ",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    },
    {
        "question": "88.Describe the connection between Project Management and an organization's Strategic Pla n.",
        "type": "shortAnswer",
        "answer": "",
        "help": "Today the emphasis is on an integrated project management process that focuses all project effort toward thestrategic plan of the organization. oach",
        "difficulty": "Level: Medium"
    }
]